<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Developer2009 &#8211; mattwhite.me</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/developer2009/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 15:24:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Developer 2009 is over</title>
		<link>/2009-4-17-developer-2009-is-over-html/</link>
					<comments>/2009-4-17-developer-2009-is-over-html/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mattwhite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2009 22:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer2009]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2009-4-17-developer-2009-is-over-html/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well my first visit to Developer2009 is over, most people are already headed to the airport and there&#8217;s a little time to chill out before my&#46;&#46;&#46;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well my first visit to Developer2009 is over, most people are already headed to the airport and there&#8217;s a little time to chill out before my flight home tomorrow.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s been a great week of catching up with old friends and meeting some new ones. This conference is very different from Lotusphere, the sessions, with the extra 30 minutes allow the presenters to get a lot more geeky and cover a lot of ground, I really enjoyed the ones that I was involved with. And, after such an incredibly busy week in January, I actually managed to get to see some of the best speakers in the business, who I had missed in Florida.</p>
<p>The nature of these events mean you&#8217;re constantly moving around between rooms, but I realised last night as we popped out to a bar on Boylston Street that I hadn&#8217;t actually been outside since Monday, not good, but it does give an impression of how busy you get, just chatting with people and finding out what other companies are doing.</p>
<p>On the XPages front, people seemed very interested and keen as ever with the new technology, hopefully we&#8217;ll see over the next year or so more people using it in a production environment as 8.5 is rolled out. From my point of view, I land on Sunday morning and then head straight off on Monday to start a new XPages project which will keep me busy for the next few months. Good times all round really.</p>
<p>Now I think it&#8217;s time to head off for a beer and some dinner.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2009-4-17-developer-2009-is-over-html/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Liveblog of The View 2009 OGS</title>
		<link>/2009-4-14-liveblog-of-the-view-2009-ogs-html/</link>
					<comments>/2009-4-14-liveblog-of-the-view-2009-ogs-html/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mattwhite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2009 19:25:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer2009]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2009-4-14-liveblog-of-the-view-2009-ogs-html/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Paul and I have set up a Cover It Live live blog for the OGS of The View 2009 conference. Bob Picciano will be keynoting so&#46;&#46;&#46;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://pmooney.net/">Paul</a> and I have set up a Cover It Live live blog for the OGS of The View 2009 conference. Bob Picciano will be keynoting so hopefully we&#8217;ll get some good content. Paul will cover admin and I&#8217;ll cover the more interesting dev stuff <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> so come here or to Pauls blog from around 08.30 EDT tomorrow:</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="http://www.coveritlive.com/index2.php/option=com_altcaster/task=viewaltcast/altcast_code=edbe444851/height=550/width=700" scrolling="no" height="550px" width="700px" frameBorder="0" ><a href="http://www.coveritlive.com/mobile.php?option=com_mobile&#038;task=viewaltcast&#038;altcast_code=edbe444851" >The View Admin/Developer 2009 Conference OGS</a></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2009-4-14-liveblog-of-the-view-2009-ogs-html/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>In Boston for Developer2009</title>
		<link>/2009-4-12-in-boston-for-developer2009-html/</link>
					<comments>/2009-4-12-in-boston-for-developer2009-html/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mattwhite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2009 23:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developer2009]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2009-4-12-in-boston-for-developer2009-html/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I flew over to Boston today a couple of days early for the Developer2009 conference that I will be attending. Possibly the quietest flight I&#8217;ve ever&#46;&#46;&#46;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I flew over to Boston today a couple of days early for the Developer2009 conference that I will be attending. Possibly the quietest flight I&#8217;ve ever been on, with plenty of space to spread out in and generally easy transfers meant I got from door to door in just over 12 hours, not bad at all.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re attending the View conferences this week, and you see me wandering around (that&#8217;s me to the right &#8211;&gt;) then please do say Hi, the best part of these Lotus community conferences is meeting new people. I&#8217;ll be presenting as well this year with sessions on Domino web development, XPages, a BOF on XPages with Pete Janzen and various other bits and pieces. It should be a good week.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2009-4-12-in-boston-for-developer2009-html/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
