<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>gsx day &#8211; mattwhite.me</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/gsx-day/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 15:24:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>GSX Day, travelling and Portland</title>
		<link>/2009-8-7-gsx-day-travelling-and-portland-html/</link>
					<comments>/2009-8-7-gsx-day-travelling-and-portland-html/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mattwhite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2009 18:20:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[My Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gsx day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iamlug]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iqjam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2009-8-7-gsx-day-travelling-and-portland-html/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After IamLUG finished up about 30 people stayed on for the GSX Day which was all about setting up your environment to monitor what&#8217;s going on,&#46;&#46;&#46;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After IamLUG finished up about 30 people stayed on for the GSX Day which was all about setting up your environment to monitor what&#8217;s going on, prevent significant outages and make everything run smoothly in your organisation. Even for a lowly developer such as myself this is useful content to know. The GSX software itself looks very interesting from a performance monitoring and scalability planning point of view and of course now that Elguji is running more and more hosted sites we need to make sure that our servers are in tip top shape.</p>
<p>The day itself was very well planned to not be a sales pitch, so the presentations were valid even without the GSX software. A very clever way of doing marketing I&#8217;d say.</p>
<p>Then yesterday really was the end of the trip to St Louis, with a very relaxed start to the day and some fun and games on the travel following that. US Airways cancelled the second leg of my flight to Portland so when I got to the front of the queue to re-book the lady looked a little shocked and said &#8220;But you&#8217;ve been booked onto the flight that leaves in 45 minutes from Terminal 2!&#8221;. Oh it was very entertaining getting my bags, changing terminals (in 111 degree heat), checking in, getting through security and boarding all within 30 minutes. But I did manage it at least so I was only half an hour late to meet Bruce and Gayle, so ultimately a successful day.</p>
<p>Today we head off to Cannon Beach on the Oregon coast to relax, catch up and spend some quality time working on IQJam. Interestingly, this is the first time that Bruce and I have actually worked in the same place before in the two years that we&#8217;ve been working together. Either we&#8217;ll get lots done or I&#8217;ll need to go back to being 5000 miles away <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2009-8-7-gsx-day-travelling-and-portland-html/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>IamLUG Day 2</title>
		<link>/2009-8-5-iamlug-day-2-html/</link>
					<comments>/2009-8-5-iamlug-day-2-html/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mattwhite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2009 13:21:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Domino Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gsx day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iamlug]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2009-8-5-iamlug-day-2-html/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The second and final day of IamLUG was jam packed with sessions including Mary Beth Raven, Jack Ratcliff talking about EXT.ND (which is looking great by&#46;&#46;&#46;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The second and final day of IamLUG was jam packed with sessions including Mary Beth Raven, Jack Ratcliff talking about <a href="http://openntf.org/Projects/pmt.nsf/ProjectLookup/Ext.nd">EXT.ND</a> (which is looking great by the way) and, of course, Rob Novak&#8217;s Free American Beer session.</p>
<p>The point being here that there was great content from some industry leading speakers. The best thing about all of the User Groups that I&#8217;ve been to, though, is the community aspect. Lots of the usual suspects are there and it&#8217;s great to catch up with them, but then you always meet interesting new people as well, it&#8217;s all about the networking.</p>
<p>The IamLUG crew did an amazing job, they really deserve what sleep they managed to get last night!</p>
<p>Today it&#8217;s onwards to the GSX day which promises to be interesting. I know it&#8217;s admin stuff, but the server performance monitoring side of things looks really useful when you want to make a very performant Domino web application. More on that tomorrow I hope.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2009-8-5-iamlug-day-2-html/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
