<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>uklug2009 &#8211; mattwhite.me</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/uklug2009/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 15:24:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>If you&#8217;re going to UKLUG&#8230;</title>
		<link>/2009-9-10-if-youre-going-to-uklug-html/</link>
					<comments>/2009-9-10-if-youre-going-to-uklug-html/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mattwhite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2009 07:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[UKLUG2009]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uklug2009]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2009-9-10-if-youre-going-to-uklug-html/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8230;we&#8217;ve been waitlisting new registrations for about a week now, even though there is still a month to go. I suspect that the announcement of Bob Picciano as the keynote speaker was what pushed us over the top so early on this year. This is great news for us, especially when conferences are suffering so [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8230;we&#8217;ve been waitlisting new registrations for about a week now, even though there is still a month to go. I suspect that the <a href="http://www.elsmore.net/warren/blog.nsf/d6plinks/WELE-7VHG95">announcement of Bob Picciano as the keynote speaker</a> was what pushed us over the top so early on this year.</p>
<p>This is great news for us, especially when conferences are suffering so much in the current economic strife. But what it does mean is that, if you&#8217;ve registered you have a certain amount of responsibility. If you do not turn up to the event then your wasted space could have been taken by someone else. Given the amazing <a href="http://www.uklug.info/UKLUG/UKLUG2009.nsf/agendas.xsp">agenda</a> that we&#8217;ve got set up, we want as many people as possible to be able to attend.</p>
<p>If you can&#8217;t make it, that&#8217;s fine, but could we please ask you to log in to the site at <a href="http://uklug.info/">http://uklug.info/</a> and click the profile link on the top right and then the &#8220;Cancel Registration&#8221; button. This will allow us to approve the next person on the wait list in your place.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2009-9-10-if-youre-going-to-uklug-html/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UKLUG Progressing</title>
		<link>/2009-5-31-uklug-progressing-html/</link>
					<comments>/2009-5-31-uklug-progressing-html/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mattwhite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2009 14:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[UKLUG2009]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[speaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uklug2009]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2009-5-31-uklug-progressing-html/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[During the week we published the first round of approved sessions on the UKLUG site. So far we have some really great looking sessions that are going to be given by stalwarts of the Lotus Community such as Rob Novak, Paul Mooney, Bill Buchan, Warren Elsmore, Steve McDonagh, Gab Davis, John Head, Ben Poole and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>During the week we published the first round of approved sessions on the <a href="http://www.uklug.info/">UKLUG site</a>. So far we have some really great looking sessions that are going to be given by stalwarts of the Lotus Community such as <a href="http://www.lotusrockstar.com/">Rob Novak</a>, <a href="http://www.pmooney.net/">Paul Mooney</a>, <a href="http://www.billbuchan.com/">Bill Buchan</a>, <a href="http://www.elsmore.net/">Warren Elsmore</a>, <a href="http://dominoyesmaybe.blogspot.com/">Steve McDonagh</a>, <a href="http://www.turtleweb.com/blog.nsf">Gab Davis</a>, <a href="http://www.johndavidhead.com/">John Head</a>, <a href="http://www.benpoole.com/">Ben Poole</a> and <a href="http://blog.collaborationmatters.com/">Stuart McIntyre</a> (amongst others), but the real beauty of events like UKLUG is that it gives an opportunity for some <a href="http://www.uklug.info/UKLUG/UKLUG2009.nsf/speakers.xsp">new speakers</a> to enter the fray as well.</p>
<p>There is still a little bit of time to get your session in if you want to get into the Lotus speaking world. As a new entrant myself, I can&#8217;t recommend it highly enough, it&#8217;s a lot of work and scary as hell, but ultimately good fun and good for your CV as well.</p>
<p>If you don&#8217;t fancy speaking and hadn&#8217;t decided whether to attend UKLUG, hopefully the <a href="http://www.uklug.info/UKLUG/UKLUG2009.nsf/sessions.xsp">sessions we&#8217;ve published</a> so far will help you make the decision.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2009-5-31-uklug-progressing-html/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
