<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: penguins	</title>
	<atom:link href="/2003-2-6-penguins-html/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2003-2-6-penguins-html/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 15:46:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Mum		</title>
		<link>/2003-2-6-penguins-html/#comment-982</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mum]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2003 06:53:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2003-2-6-penguins-html/#comment-982</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;We, too, saw penguins on the Cape penninsula yesterday - becoming a family hangup?!! Hope you got our email from Cape Point. The weather has been windy but hot - the wind now dropped and we are off to Robben Island (Mandela&#039;s prison) by catamaran today. The hotel is absolutely fantastic and I will not want to do anything when we get back. Very nice group of people to travel with. Love to everyone who logs on to see your sight - several hotels that we visit have this internet service available (free!!) Give our love to Rotorua and think of Therese&lt;/p&gt;]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We, too, saw penguins on the Cape penninsula yesterday &#8211; becoming a family hangup?!! Hope you got our email from Cape Point. The weather has been windy but hot &#8211; the wind now dropped and we are off to Robben Island (Mandela&#8217;s prison) by catamaran today. The hotel is absolutely fantastic and I will not want to do anything when we get back. Very nice group of people to travel with. Love to everyone who logs on to see your sight &#8211; several hotels that we visit have this internet service available (free!!) Give our love to Rotorua and think of Therese</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
