<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>london &#8211; mattwhite.me</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/london/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 15:24:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Announcing XPages101 &#8211; An Introduction to XPages course</title>
		<link>/2009-12-4-announcing-xpages101-an-introduction-to-xpages-course-html/</link>
					<comments>/2009-12-4-announcing-xpages101-an-introduction-to-xpages-course-html/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mattwhite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2009 09:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[XPages]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[london]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xpages101]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2009-12-4-announcing-xpages101-an-introduction-to-xpages-course-html/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A few weeks ago I asked the twittersphere what people thought would be a reasonable cost for a one day long, introduction to XPages course. This&#46;&#46;&#46;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks ago I <a href="http://twitter.com/mattwhite/status/5040230767">asked the twittersphere</a> what people thought would be a reasonable cost for a one day long, introduction to XPages course. This was before I had investigated the cost of anything such as room hire etc, and also before I had thought about what the content for the course might be. But I liked the idea of running a single day bootcamp that will help you get started with XPages so, taking people&#8217;s advice and sourcing all of the elements for the course, I&#8217;m happy to be able to open up <a href="http://xpages101.net/">xpages101.net</a> today.</p>
<p> I&#8217;ve managed to find a very reasonably priced training room, and more importantly, written a sample application which includes as much of the elements of a &#8220;real world&#8221; XPages app as I could squeeze into an eight hour course. The plan for the day is that you bring along your own laptop with Domino Designer 8.5.1 installed, I give you a starting point template and then together we go through the steps to build an XPages application. As we progress we&#8217;ll cover all of the major elements of XPages including the new design elements, server side Javascript, Dojo, OneUI and Themes, searching and so on. Then at the end of the day you&#8217;ll have a working application (in theory at least!) and be able to go back to your office and use it as a reference point for your first real world development when you deploy Domino 8.5.1.</p>
<p> So please do head on over to <a href="http://xpages101.net/">xpages101.net</a>, have a look at the site and if you&#8217;ve got any questions <a href="http://xpages101.net/training/xpages101.nsf/contact.xsp">drop me a line</a>, otherwise I hope to see you in London in February 2010.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2009-12-4-announcing-xpages101-an-introduction-to-xpages-course-html/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The daily constitutional</title>
		<link>/2009-6-24-the-daily-constitutional-html/</link>
					<comments>/2009-6-24-the-daily-constitutional-html/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mattwhite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2009 12:31:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[My Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[london]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[walking]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2009-6-24-the-daily-constitutional-html/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been working from home pretty much exclusively for over a year now and I really like the more relaxed way of doing things. I can&#46;&#46;&#46;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="full-image-float-right ssNonEditable"><span><a title="IMG_0010 by 11tmr, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/11tmr/3656274801/"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/3656274801_6089194e90.jpg" alt="IMG_0010" width="375" height="500" /></a></span></span></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been working from home pretty much exclusively for over a year now and I really like the more relaxed way of doing things. I can decide my own hours, work when it suits me.</p>
<p>On the flip side, it would be very easy to never leave the flat. So I have tried to get into the routine of heading out for a couple of hours from about 11am every day to stretch the legs and clear the head. This is when living in central London, in the summer really pays off. It really can be a great city.</p>
<p>For example, today part of my walk was from <a href="http://www.walkit.com/walk/?city=london&amp;from=westminster+tube&amp;fuid=384494_424819&amp;to=bond+street+tube&amp;tuid=389351_427350&amp;rta=old&amp;direct=1">Westminster Underground to Bond Street</a>, through St James&#8217; Park and across the Mall (pictured). On a day like today when the weather is sunny and warm, but not too warm. Not too many tourists, life doesn&#8217;t really get much better.</p>
<p>So if you&#8217;ve never been to London, I highly recommend visiting and walking, it really is a surprisingly compact place once you get your bearings. The tube, taxis and buses are fine if you&#8217;re in a hurry, but if you&#8217;re inside Zone 1, then it&#8217;s normally as quick to walk and much more interesting.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2009-6-24-the-daily-constitutional-html/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
