<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: driven	</title>
	<atom:link href="/2003-2-27-driven-html/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2003-2-27-driven-html/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 15:46:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Fi &#38; Si		</title>
		<link>/2003-2-27-driven-html/#comment-967</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fi &#38; Si]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2003 15:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2003-2-27-driven-html/#comment-967</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Glad to hear that you got home alright Eiblis and Richard. We&#039;re still right in holiday mode but will also have to cope with the shock of work come Monday. Have decided to take it easy today as we got in last night at twenty to two - having been out for curry and beers in the East Village. We ended up in New York&#039;s oldest bar which serves two types of beer, light and dark. Fortunately both are nice. See you soon Fi and Si&lt;/p&gt;]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Glad to hear that you got home alright Eiblis and Richard. We&#8217;re still right in holiday mode but will also have to cope with the shock of work come Monday. Have decided to take it easy today as we got in last night at twenty to two &#8211; having been out for curry and beers in the East Village. We ended up in New York&#8217;s oldest bar which serves two types of beer, light and dark. Fortunately both are nice. See you soon Fi and Si</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Mum		</title>
		<link>/2003-2-27-driven-html/#comment-966</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mum]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2003 08:54:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2003-2-27-driven-html/#comment-966</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;The M25 certainly was not like that yesterday morning! - however, Dad and I had a reasonable journey home. The weather in England was better than we had hoped but after 3 weeks it is hard to get back into gear. How you are going to feel i dread to think. Dealing with the rail company has at least got your mind back to a working environment! All here fine - looking forward to seeing everyone again.&lt;/p&gt;]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The M25 certainly was not like that yesterday morning! &#8211; however, Dad and I had a reasonable journey home. The weather in England was better than we had hoped but after 3 weeks it is hard to get back into gear. How you are going to feel i dread to think. Dealing with the rail company has at least got your mind back to a working environment! All here fine &#8211; looking forward to seeing everyone again.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
