<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>dannotes &#8211; mattwhite.me</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/dannotes/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 15:24:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Dannotes and a long journey home</title>
		<link>/2010-4-15-dannotes-and-a-long-journey-home-html/</link>
					<comments>/2010-4-15-dannotes-and-a-long-journey-home-html/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mattwhite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 11:37:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Domino Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dannotes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2010-4-15-dannotes-and-a-long-journey-home-html/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been in Denmark for a couple of days now at the wonderful Dannotes event. It&#8217;s a slightly different setup compared to other user groups that I&#8217;ve been to, but as with all user groups, the organisation behind the scenes is amazing, the people are interesting and good company, and there are interesting conversations happening [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been in Denmark for a couple of days now at the wonderful Dannotes event. It&#8217;s a slightly different setup compared to other user groups that I&#8217;ve been to, but as with all user groups, the organisation behind the scenes is amazing, the people are interesting and good company, and there are interesting conversations happening everywhere you look.</p>
<p>I ended up presenting the full version of Tim Clark and my Lotusphere session. If you saw it in Florida then you&#8217;ll know that we had too much content to get through. Well luckily here I had three hours to speak so was able to finish the entire presentation for the first time. It seemed to go pretty well with some interesting questions and only one mistake from me. My lesson from the afternoon is that talking and coding for three hours is really hard work, though I suppose I should have been able to guess that beforehand.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve been looked after by the organisers here really well. The hotel is ideal for a user group meeting, the restaurant was very nice and the beer and wine flowed freely (possibly a little too freely judging by some people this morning).</p>
<p>And then we get onto the volcanic eruption. The upshot of several hours on the phone and internet is that we&#8217;re stuck here until Saturday. So given that I am travelling with Warren &#8220;Mr Lego&#8221; Elsmore, I&#8217;m sure you won&#8217;t be too surprised to find we&#8217;re heading to Legoland after Dannotes wraps up for an&nbsp;impromptu&nbsp;visit. Then tomorrow it&#8217;s into Copenhagen before, hopefully, heading home on Saturday. At the moment that is all entirely theoretical as the airlines don&#8217;t know when they&#8217;ll be able to operate again. I suppose you just have to make the most of an unexpected opportunity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2010-4-15-dannotes-and-a-long-journey-home-html/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
