<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>My Life &#8211; mattwhite.me</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/my-life/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 15:24:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Heading home</title>
		<link>/2010-8-6-heading-home-html/</link>
					<comments>/2010-8-6-heading-home-html/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mattwhite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2010 23:53:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[My Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iamlug]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tackiton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xpages101]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2010-8-6-heading-home-html/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It seems like a long time since I went away on holiday, and it is. Since the middle of July I&#8217;ve been to Latitude (great), Madeira&#46;&#46;&#46;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It seems like a long time since I went away on holiday, and it is. Since the middle of July I&#8217;ve been to <a href="http://www.latitudefestival.co.uk/">Latitude</a> (great), Madeira (great), <a href="http://iamlug.org/iamlug/IamLug2010.nsf">IamLUG</a> (great) and run an <a href="http://xpages101.net/">XPages101</a> day (seemed to go well). So all in all it&#8217;s been a really enjoyable few weeks.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m sat in JFK airport in New York waiting to start the final leg of the journey home and much as it&#8217;s been a great couple of weeks away, I am *really* looking forward to getting back home and just decompressing for a couple of days before getting back into the real world with a vengeance on Monday morning.</p>
<p>IamLUG was a really superb event, <a href="http://idonotes.com/">Chris</a> and the rest of the team do put on a good show. Everything was run incredibly smoothly, the content was very good indeed and, as ever, the people were great company. I presented my &#8220;<a href="http://mattwhite.me/iamlug_tenpatterns.zip">Ten XPages Design Patterns</a>&#8221; session, probably for the last time as I&#8217;ve used it for a year now. So I need to start thinking about future sessions pretty seriously now. (Bet you can&#8217;t guess what I plan to speak about next time!).</p>
<p>After IamLUG, we had the inaugural &#8220;<a href="http://tackiton.com/">Tack It On</a>&#8221; day, and I&#8217;d really like to thank <a href="http://www.lotusnotebook.com/">David Leedy</a> for his invaluable assistance during the day. I had been rather lax and not given him a huge amount of guidance before the day itself but he dealt with all of the questions with good grace and humour. Things really wouldn&#8217;t have run as smoothly without him there. Overall I think the day went pretty well. I&#8217;m sure there&#8217;ll be more of these sorts of things happening in the future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2010-8-6-heading-home-html/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gone fishing</title>
		<link>/2010-7-15-gone-fishing-html/</link>
					<comments>/2010-7-15-gone-fishing-html/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mattwhite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2010 16:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[My Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iamlug]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2010-7-15-gone-fishing-html/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well it doesn&#8217;t happen very often (it&#8217;s over two years since I last took a proper holiday), but I&#8217;m off on holidays for the next two&#46;&#46;&#46;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well it doesn&#8217;t happen very often (it&#8217;s over two years since I last took a proper holiday), but I&#8217;m off on holidays for the next two weeks. This weekend we&#8217;re heading up to Suffolk to the <a href="http://www.latitudefestival.co.uk/home/">Latitude Festival</a> and then later next week it&#8217;s off to <a href="http://www.madeira-web.com/">Madeira</a> for a family trip where we&#8217;ll be celebrating important birthdays for my parents amongst other things.</p>
<p>When I get back from holidays I literally switch airports and fly straight off to St Louis for the <a href="http://iamlug.org/">IamLUG</a> conference. (If you&#8217;ve not <a href="http://iamlug.org/">registered for it</a> and the <a href="http://tackiton.com/">Tack It On</a> day which follows then what have you been doing?)</p>
<p>So all in all it&#8217;s going to be a fun few weeks. But if I don&#8217;t respond to your email you&#8217;ll know why.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2010-7-15-gone-fishing-html/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The great geek escape</title>
		<link>/2010-4-19-the-great-geek-escape-html/</link>
					<comments>/2010-4-19-the-great-geek-escape-html/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mattwhite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 10:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[My Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greatgeekescape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2010-4-19-the-great-geek-escape-html/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As you may know if you follow Warren or myself on Twitter, we reached the point on Saturday morning where it became fairly obvious (to us&#46;&#46;&#46;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As you may know if you follow <a href="http://elsmore.net/">Warren</a> or myself on <a href="http://twitter.com/mattwhite">Twitter</a><a>, we reached the point on Saturday morning where it became fairly obvious (to us at least) that we weren&#8217;t going to get home by plane from Copenhagen any time soon. The only option that was available to us was a Eurostar journey from Paris to London on Monday evening. So after booking various train tickets (Thalys from Brussels to Paris, Eurostar from Paris to London), extending the car hire and making it a one way rental that we could drop in Brussels, buying supplies for the trip, we set out early on Sunday morning for the </a><a href="http://twitter.com/#search?q=%23greatgeekescape">#greatgeekescape</a>.</p>
<p>The plan was simple, drive from Copenhagen to Brussels, drop the car there, sleep, train to Paris, train to London and then home (for me at least, Warren still has to get to Edinburgh from there). So Sunday was spent driving&#8230; a long way. 1050km (650 miles). In a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fiat_Nuova_500">Fiat 500</a>. It took us 12 hours, but we finally made it at around 8pm, absolutely exhausted, but a lot closer to home.</p>
<p>This whole episode has raised several points and questions&#8230;</p>
<ol>
<li>Danish drivers are scarily aggressive, for such a relaxed nation I have no idea where this trait comes from.</li>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Smokey_and_the_Bandit#Soundtrack">&#8220;East bound and down&#8221;</a>, the theme from Smokey and the Bandit, is a perfect tune to play loud while blatting along German autobahns in an Italian car while trying to get to Belgium.</li>
<li>It is inconsiderate of the Dutch road building authorities to redesign their road system without checking with us first, we saw entirely too much of the Eindhoven ring road. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></li>
<li>When you have <a href="http://yfrog.com/16pkqmj">two laptops, two smartphones, and a GPS system</a> you can navigate your way around unexpectedly changed Dutch roads in a pinch!</li>
<li>It&#8217;s useful having Twitter and SMS to help us out with support from friends, and also people to answer questions for us.</li>
<li>We were very very lucky that we had the funds and opportunity to decide to get ourselves home. Not everyone was in the same position and I can&#8217;t imagine how bad this would have been otherwise.</li>
<li>There is absolutely no way I could do any serious amount of travel on a regular basis. Even before this whole escapade I was knackered from trips to Belgium, Amsterdam and Newcastle earlier in the month. I really just want to get home.</li>
<li>In all of the people we encountered on phones, in hotels, in bars, across multiple countries, the single common factor was unfailing helpfulness and, given the stress some were under, a cheerful response to questions. Sometimes your faith in humanity can get a welcome boost.</li>
</ol>
<p>All being well, and I hope I&#8217;m not tempting fate here, the Eurostar will get us back to St Pancras at 10pm this evening. I can get home in 30 minutes from there and Warren has another night away from home with friends as he continues up to Edinburgh.</p>
<p>All in all it&#8217;s been an eventful and memorable trip away from home. Not one I&#8217;d like to repeat any time soon though!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2010-4-19-the-great-geek-escape-html/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>XPages Workshop in Amsterdam</title>
		<link>/2010-4-7-xpages-workshop-in-amsterdam-html/</link>
					<comments>/2010-4-7-xpages-workshop-in-amsterdam-html/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mattwhite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2010 10:13:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[My Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xpages workshop]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2010-4-7-xpages-workshop-in-amsterdam-html/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I flew over from to Amsterdam from London this morning (easiest journey ever by the way, City airport shows that it is possible to have a&#46;&#46;&#46;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I flew over from to Amsterdam from London this morning (easiest journey ever by the way, City airport shows that it is possible to have a vaguely pleasant travel experience still) to prepare for the <a href="http://www.clearitconsulting.nl/site/blog.nsf/dx/08-02-2010155139CDRKFG.htm">two day XPages course</a> which I&#8217;m helping to run with <a href="http://www.clearitconsulting.nl/">Clear IT Consulting</a> this week.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve not been to Amsterdam for about 18 months, and I suspect I won&#8217;t see much of the city this trip, but I do like it a lot over here.</p>
<p>This is continuing what is, for me at least, a busy month of travel with Belgium last week, a trip to Newcastle this weekend on which I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;ll hear more (although not maybe in the blogosphere), and then Denmark next week. It&#8217;s good to do travel some times and I&#8217;m lucky enough to be an infrequent enough flyer that it&#8217;s still a novelty for me. So I&#8217;m planted in the hotel this afternoon just continuing with my normal development work and then heading over the training room this evening to make sure everything is set up for tomorrow morning.</p>
<p>As <a href="http://benpoole.com/">Ben</a> says, &#8220;Ah the life of the jet setting freelancer&#8221;. Indeed.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2010-4-7-xpages-workshop-in-amsterdam-html/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Settlers of Catan</title>
		<link>/2010-3-21-the-settlers-of-catan-html/</link>
					<comments>/2010-3-21-the-settlers-of-catan-html/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mattwhite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2010 19:59:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[My Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fun]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2010-3-21-the-settlers-of-catan-html/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s been one of those really great weekends where everything is very chilled out and goes right. One of those things was an evening last night&#46;&#46;&#46;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been one of those really great weekends where everything is very chilled out and goes right. One of those things was an evening last night playing a board game that had completely passed me by until now.</p>
<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Settlers_of_Catan">The Settlers of Catan</a> is like a cross between Monopoly, Risk and Civilisation. Our single game lasted around three hours and generated a huge amount of bargaining, nastiness and laughter. If you&#8217;re looking for a game which will while away several hours, requires a lot of strategy and is actually quite challenging then this is the game for you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2010-3-21-the-settlers-of-catan-html/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Big Libel Gig</title>
		<link>/2010-3-15-the-big-libel-gig-html/</link>
					<comments>/2010-3-15-the-big-libel-gig-html/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mattwhite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2010 09:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[My Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2010-3-15-the-big-libel-gig-html/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last night was the Libel Reform Big Libel Gig in central London. A benefit evening to raise money for Dr Simon Singh to continue the libel&#46;&#46;&#46;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last night was the <a href="http://libelreform.org/the-big-libel-gig">Libel Reform Big Libel Gig</a> in central London. A benefit evening to raise money for <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simon_Singh#Chiropractic_lawsuit_and_backlash">Dr Simon Singh</a> to continue the libel court battle he is currently defending (and has been fighting for two years now). The serious element of this is that the libel laws in the UK are ludicrous. It is very very easy to get sued (and not just by people from the UK, we are currently the home of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Libel_tourism">libel tourism</a> for the rest of the world due to the inequities of our legal system), and very very difficult to win. Even if you do win, as in the case of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ben_Goldacre">Ben Goldacre</a>, then you are still likely to be massively out of pocket on costs.</p>
<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robin_Ince">Robin Ince</a> has a very nice sideline in setting up these benefit / multi performer evenings. By all accounts last night was quite similar to one of the Nine Lessons For Godless People evenings at Christmas. This is &#8220;a good thing&#8221;. When you&#8217;re able to get Marcus Brigstocke, Ed Byrne, Shappi Khorsandi, Brian Cox (yes he of Lotusphere 2010 fame), Simon Singh, Richard Wiseman, Ben Goldacre, Dara O Briain and Tim Minchin into less than four hours, you&#8217;re onto a winner!</p>
<p>Of the evening, I thought Marcus Brigstocke, Brian Cox and Dara O Briain were just superb. Very funny, and inspiring.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s more important is that the money raising continues for the legal battles that are currently going on. You can find out more at <a href="http://libelreform.org/">libelreform.org</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2010-3-15-the-big-libel-gig-html/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review of the Year &#8211; 2009</title>
		<link>/2009-12-28-review-of-the-year-2009-html/</link>
					<comments>/2009-12-28-review-of-the-year-2009-html/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mattwhite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2009 15:13:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[My Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2009-12-28-review-of-the-year-2009-html/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every year, for the last several, I&#8217;ve done a blog post sometime between Christmas and New Year that wraps up my life over the previous 12&#46;&#46;&#46;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every year, for the last several, I&#8217;ve done a blog post sometime between Christmas and New Year that wraps up my life over the previous 12 months. Normally there has been some big change, but this year has been more evolutionary than revolutionary.</p>
<p>As ever, the year started with Lotusphere, but it was a very different one for me for two reasons, I was speaking for the first time and it was a great (if pant wettingly scary) experience, one that I hope to continue for a few years to come. Indeed <a href="http://blog.tc-soft.com/">Tim Clark</a> and I will be presenting in less than three weeks at Lotusphere 2010. The other big change at Lotusphere 2009 was that <a href="http://elguji.com/">Elguji</a> had a stand on the Showcase floor. It gives a totally different view on the proceedings, still great fun of course, and also something that we&#8217;ll be repeating in a few weeks time.</p>
<p>The public speaking continued on a couple of fronts throughout the year with sessions at The View Developer 2009, IamLUG and UKLUG. All great events in their own way. The user group scene continues to expand and get better every year. There are several European groups that I&#8217;m going to try and get to during 2010. The speaking is the biggest new thing for me this year. If you&#8217;re unsure about getting started, all I can say is that I highly recommend it. And this is coming from an introvert who was pathologically scared of public speaking until recently.</p>
<p>In parallel to the conferences and user groups, I was lucky enough to continue to get invited along to various XPages courses run by IBM. XPages has been the constant technology throughout the year for me. From January when we released the XPages version of <a href="http://ideajam.net/">IdeaJam</a> through to later in the year and the release of <a href="http://iqjam.net/">IQJam</a>. And into 2010 with my new <a href="http://xpages101.net/">XPages101 course</a> that&#8217;s running in February.</p>
<p>Elguji has been the main constant during the year. We&#8217;ve had some great success in sales of IdeaJam to more companies, government organisations and, more publicly with the Lotus Knows IdeaJam in August. It continues to be great fun, and to keep things moving along we added lots of new features to IdeaJam and a whole new product called IQJam. Launching in November we&#8217;ve already had encouraging sales to both existing IdeaJam customers and new customers for Elguji, in both cases people seem really excited about the possibilities with the tool that we have created. Working with <a href="http://bruceelgort.com/">Bruce</a> and <a href="http://gayleelgort.wordpress.com/">Gayle</a> has been the most rewarding thing I&#8217;ve done in my professional life, we&#8217;re building a really nice little company, but more importantly having fun as we go.</p>
<p>While Elguji has taken up a large portion of my time, I&#8217;ve also been working on some cool consulting projects as well. <a href="http://www.mickmoignard.com/">Mick Moignard</a> and I created an XPages application which was both challenging and interesting (thank the Lord for the arrival of 8.5.1 is all I&#8217;ll say!), and the <a href="http://londondevelopercoop.com/">LDC</a> grouping of independent developers continues to offer some interesting opportunities. Even when we&#8217;re all off doing our own thing then it&#8217;s good to have people like <a href="http://benpoole.com/">Ben</a>, <a href="http://blog.woowar.com/">Julian</a>, <a href="http://stickfight.co.uk/">Mark</a> and <a href="http://www.inter-weavers.com/0/RobsBlog.nsf">Rob</a> around to run problems past (and maybe have the occasional beverage with as well).</p>
<p>There was no ILUG 2009 which made UKLUG all the bigger. We all decamped up to Edinburgh, people flew in from all over the world and, for two days, everyone seemed to have an amazing time. Lots of new friendships were made, late nights were had, large Martinis drunk. Roll on all of the user groups next year is all I can say.</p>
<p>The blurring of work and personal lives continue with more and more people using Twitter to keep in contact, the never ending Skype chats. To make things even more blurred, this year has also included a wonderful trip to Vancouver, WA to see Bruce, Gayle and family, walking weekends in Northern Ireland and Yorkshire. Hopefully the walking weekends will continue into next year.</p>
<p>Other than that, a 2010 that is as good as 2009 would be fine with me, but why not be greedy? 2010 is looking very positive, hopefully it is for you as well.</p>
<p>&lt;/2009&gt;</p>
<p>&lt;/noughties&gt;</p>
<p>&lt;teens&gt;</p>
<p>&lt;2010&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2009-12-28-review-of-the-year-2009-html/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Merry Christmas one and all</title>
		<link>/2009-12-25-merry-christmas-one-and-all-html/</link>
					<comments>/2009-12-25-merry-christmas-one-and-all-html/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mattwhite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2009 09:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[My Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas greetings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2009-12-25-merry-christmas-one-and-all-html/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, I&#8217;m off to Suffolk for the Christmas break to see the family. Here&#8217;s wishing you and your family a wonderful Christmas. Now, where was that&#46;&#46;&#46;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, I&#8217;m off to Suffolk for the Christmas break to see the family.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s wishing you and your family a wonderful Christmas. Now, where was that bottle of champagne?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2009-12-25-merry-christmas-one-and-all-html/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Back online</title>
		<link>/2009-8-16-back-online-html/</link>
					<comments>/2009-8-16-back-online-html/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mattwhite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2009 14:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[My Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[busy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2009-8-16-back-online-html/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well after a couple of truly relaxing weeks on IamLUG, visiting Bruce and Gayle, driving down to San Francisco from Vancouver, WA and finally having my&#46;&#46;&#46;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well after a couple of truly relaxing weeks on IamLUG, visiting Bruce and Gayle, driving down to San Francisco from Vancouver, WA and finally having my brother and his family visit for the weekend, (phew!) it&#8217;s time to get back to the real world.</p>
<p>Over the next couple of weeks we have the Lotus Knows IdeaJam kicking off, more work on IQJam, finishing off the development for the next version of IdeaJam and plenty of other fun projects to fill in the gaps in between.&nbsp;The build up to UKLUG is also about to start in earnest as well.</p>
<p>Life is busy, but life is good. Now if only I could shake off this damn jetlag then all would be perfect.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2009-8-16-back-online-html/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cannon Beach x 2</title>
		<link>/2009-8-11-cannon-beach-x-2-html/</link>
					<comments>/2009-8-11-cannon-beach-x-2-html/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mattwhite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2009 01:59:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[My Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[holiday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2009-8-11-cannon-beach-x-2-html/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We headed out to the Stephanie Inn at Cannon Beach for the weekend and had the most relaxing few days of the year so far, wine,&#46;&#46;&#46;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We headed out to the <a href="http://www.stephanie-inn.com/">Stephanie Inn</a> at Cannon Beach for the weekend and had the most relaxing few days of the year so far, wine, good company and just general chill-axing.</p>
<p>So relaxing, in fact, that I managed to forget my jacket which I had left my passport in! So after heading back to Bruce and Gayle&#8217;s house yesterday, this morning it was up early to head back out to the beach to get the passport so I can get home later in the week. To be honest, it wasn&#8217;t a bad thing to happen as the drive through the hills outside Portland was stunning and it meant I got to enjoy even more of Route 101 which runs right down the west coast of the States. Lots of cliffs, beaches, forests and sun make for an interesting and enjoyable drive.</p>
<p>I really am going to struggle to get my head back in gear when I get home on Thursday. But until then I have another couple of days to enjoy. So back to the balcony here in Gold Beach to watch the sunset.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2009-8-11-cannon-beach-x-2-html/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
