<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: macquarrie	</title>
	<atom:link href="/2003-2-19-macquarrie-html/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2003-2-19-macquarrie-html/</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 15:46:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Mum		</title>
		<link>/2003-2-19-macquarrie-html/#comment-977</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mum]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2003 13:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2003-2-19-macquarrie-html/#comment-977</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;I have just typed a huge screed which did not submit!! Great to hear you are having a good time matthew - keep on with the suncream and hat! Hope Si and fi have a good trip and love to J &amp;M Dad and I in J,burg. Having left Cape Town we drove through the Karoo and up the gardenn route up the coast, flew to Durban where it was hot and sticky and not very safe and have now flown to J,burg. Fr Tony joining us tonight.&lt;/p&gt;]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have just typed a huge screed which did not submit!! Great to hear you are having a good time matthew &#8211; keep on with the suncream and hat! Hope Si and fi have a good trip and love to J &#038;M Dad and I in J,burg. Having left Cape Town we drove through the Karoo and up the gardenn route up the coast, flew to Durban where it was hot and sticky and not very safe and have now flown to J,burg. Fr Tony joining us tonight.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Mum		</title>
		<link>/2003-2-19-macquarrie-html/#comment-976</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mum]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2003 12:56:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2003-2-19-macquarrie-html/#comment-976</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Matthew et al, Sounds like you are having a great time! Keep putting the sun cream on and the hat in that car!! Dad and I have left Cape Town (the tour guide we had was great and we are likely to try and arrange a private wine tour through him for the wine gang in the future) We travelled by coach through part of the Karoo and up the garden route in the coast (eating ostrich etc) to Port Elizabeth then flew to Durban - very hot and humid there and di not feel very safe. We have now flown to J&#039;burg and are back in a hotel with email facilities. Fr Tony is joining us for a meal tonnight and tomorrow we vist Pretoria then on to the game reserve. Hope Simon and Fi have a wonderful; trip - it&#039;s going to be a colde one!! J - glad all is going well - did Uncle Kev get his stuff there? Just to let you all know that it looks as if we can have a family get togehter on the weekend of 15th March so bring all the photos for a hard weekend&#039;s looking!! Love to all...&lt;/p&gt;]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Matthew et al, Sounds like you are having a great time! Keep putting the sun cream on and the hat in that car!! Dad and I have left Cape Town (the tour guide we had was great and we are likely to try and arrange a private wine tour through him for the wine gang in the future) We travelled by coach through part of the Karoo and up the garden route in the coast (eating ostrich etc) to Port Elizabeth then flew to Durban &#8211; very hot and humid there and di not feel very safe. We have now flown to J&#8217;burg and are back in a hotel with email facilities. Fr Tony is joining us for a meal tonnight and tomorrow we vist Pretoria then on to the game reserve. Hope Simon and Fi have a wonderful; trip &#8211; it&#8217;s going to be a colde one!! J &#8211; glad all is going well &#8211; did Uncle Kev get his stuff there? Just to let you all know that it looks as if we can have a family get togehter on the weekend of 15th March so bring all the photos for a hard weekend&#8217;s looking!! Love to all&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
