<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>holiday &#8211; mattwhite.me</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/holiday/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 15:24:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Cannon Beach x 2</title>
		<link>/2009-8-11-cannon-beach-x-2-html/</link>
					<comments>/2009-8-11-cannon-beach-x-2-html/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mattwhite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2009 01:59:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[My Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[holiday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2009-8-11-cannon-beach-x-2-html/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We headed out to the Stephanie Inn at Cannon Beach for the weekend and had the most relaxing few days of the year so far, wine,&#46;&#46;&#46;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We headed out to the <a href="http://www.stephanie-inn.com/">Stephanie Inn</a> at Cannon Beach for the weekend and had the most relaxing few days of the year so far, wine, good company and just general chill-axing.</p>
<p>So relaxing, in fact, that I managed to forget my jacket which I had left my passport in! So after heading back to Bruce and Gayle&#8217;s house yesterday, this morning it was up early to head back out to the beach to get the passport so I can get home later in the week. To be honest, it wasn&#8217;t a bad thing to happen as the drive through the hills outside Portland was stunning and it meant I got to enjoy even more of Route 101 which runs right down the west coast of the States. Lots of cliffs, beaches, forests and sun make for an interesting and enjoyable drive.</p>
<p>I really am going to struggle to get my head back in gear when I get home on Thursday. But until then I have another couple of days to enjoy. So back to the balcony here in Gold Beach to watch the sunset.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2009-8-11-cannon-beach-x-2-html/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Matt is out of the office</title>
		<link>/2009-8-2-matt-is-out-of-the-office-html/</link>
					<comments>/2009-8-2-matt-is-out-of-the-office-html/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mattwhite]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2009 11:58:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[My Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[holiday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iamlug]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2009-8-2-matt-is-out-of-the-office-html/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I flew out to St Louis yesterday, a long but relatively easy journey. As soon as I arrived I started bumping into IamLUG attendees and shared&#46;&#46;&#46;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I flew out to St Louis yesterday, a long but relatively easy journey. As soon as I arrived I started bumping into <a href="http://iamlug.org/">IamLUG</a> attendees and shared a few (surprisingly nice) beers with a few of the gang before crashing quite early due to the long day.</p>
<p>Today it&#8217;s off to the baseball to see St Louis play Houston which should be fun. And then tomorrow it&#8217;s into the conference proper. From what I&#8217;ve seen so far <a href="http://idonotes.com/">Chris</a> and team have done an amazing job, the hotel is ideal with large rooms, nice public areas and helpful staff. Can&#8217;t wait to get into it.</p>
<p>Following the conference I&#8217;m heading off on tour to go and see Bruce and Gayle so I&#8217;ll be checking email but not nearly as much as normal. If I don&#8217;t get back to you, then you&#8217;ll know why!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2009-8-2-matt-is-out-of-the-office-html/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
